# Mick Rudolph

linkedin.com/in/mickrudolph | SLC, UT 84124 801.232.0957 | rudolph.mick@gmail.com | Portfolio: mickrudolphdesign.com

User experience researcher and visual design professional passionate about understanding how people interact with their digital environment and discovering simple, intuitive solutions to everyday problems. Strengths in qualitative research, teamwork, and visual design. A background and bachelor's degree in business marketing lends itself to my ability to empathize with a product user based on data and research.

# **Technical Skills**

HTML, CSS, GitHub, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, UI Grids and Composition, Color Theory, Heuristic Evaluation, Typography, Interaction Design and Iconography, Storyboarding, Decision Flow Diagrams, User Need Identification, User Experience Interviewing, Persona Creation, Insight Synthesis, VBA, Tableau, R Studio, MS Office, Adobe Creative Suite, Google Ad Words, Facebook Ads

# **Projects**

# UX Design Project | <a href="https://mickrudolphdesign.com/#project1">https://mickrudolphdesign.com/#project1</a>

My team's final project for the UX/UI Bootcamp, the goal of this project was to design a website that related to a social issue. My group and I recognized an opportunity to create an informational website aimed at helping users understand their individual impact on the environment.

• Skills | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Adobe XD, Miro, Prototyping, Usability Testing, User Research (Interviews + Surveys) & Analysis

# Local App | https://mickrudolphdesign.com/#project2

While there is a wide variety of preference regarding vacationing, many travelers want a "local" experience when they go on vacation, without the cost of a tour guide. Local is an answer to this traveling issue in the form of an app that connects travelers with locals who are willing to take travelers on personalized tours of events, activities, or destinations.

• Skills | Adobe XD, Miro, Prototyping, Figma, Usability Testing, User Research (Interviews + Qualtrics Surveys) & Analysis

# Arden App | https://mickrudolphdesign.com/#project3

Arden is a goal-setting app that incorporates an innovative visual representation of user's goals progress. After conducting user research, my team and I realized that though many people have personal goals, many people struggle to keep their goals. Our goal was to discover a engaging and motivating way to help people make and keep goals.

• Skills | Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Miro, Figma, Prototyping, Usability Testing, User Research (Interviews + Surveys) & Analysis

# 

<u>Purelements</u> is a non-profit based in Brooklyn, NY that offers dance, theater, and arts intensive programs for black youth. My team's goal was to redesign this website, emphasizing navigational ease-of-use while infusing Purelement's colorful and vibrant culture.

• Skills | Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Miro, Prototyping, Usability Testing, User Research (Interviews + Surveys) & Analysis

#### **EDUCATION**

University of UtahSalt Lake City, UTCertificate, UX/UIMar 2021

# **Brigham Young University - Marriott School of Business**

Provo, UT Dec 2021

Bachelor of Science, Marketing

■ GPA 3.49/4.00

- Director of Senior Involvement | Marketing Association
- Scholarships: Stoddard Career Advancement (merit), BYU (Academic), G. Roger and M. Victor (merit)
- Certifications: Griffin Hill Sales Systems

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Brigham Young University Business Career Center**

Provo, UT

Marketing Coordinator

Oct 2019 - Aug 2020

Executed a promotional campaign resulting in 50% of Marriott School student product utilization

Cummins Shoreview, MN

Marketing Communications Intern

Jun 2019 – Aug 2019

- Developed and implemented a lead nurture program to qualify 360,000+ leads via an email campaign
- Integrated visual brand strategy in a showcase site that experiences 700+ traffic of target market annually

### **Utah Community Credit Union**

Provo, UT

BaZing Sales Business Development Intern

Jan 2019 – Apr 2019

- Generated traffic for 80+ small businesses by selling benefits of the BaZing merchant program
   Social Media Marketing Intern
   Sep 2017 Jan 2019
- Boosted social media following 250% by creating and implementing a comprehensive content strategy
- Increased content engagement 8x, enhancing brand awareness and perception with key target audiences
- Managed UCCU's online presence by fulfilling all communications on all social media platforms
   Assistant Vault Teller

  Dec 2015 Sep 2017
- Amplified branch cross-sales by 50% by formulating a revamped incentive program
- Improved member loyalty and branch culture by making the commitment to learn every member's name

#### 97th Floor (Digital Marketing Agency)

Lehi, UT

Marketing Intern

*May 2018 – Jul 2018* 

- Generated a 30% climb in Google's SERP for 7 clients' webpages through keyword research and SEO
- Increased workflow efficiency by developing a strategy for internal linking to authoritative pages
- Simplified the optimization process for writers by creating keyword and TF-IDF centric page outlines

# SERVICE

# **Symbii Home Health & Hospice**

Orem, UT

Hospice Volunteer

Sep 2016 – Jan 2017

Visited and showed compassion to two clients on hospice on a weekly basis

# **Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints**

Rancho Cucamonga, California

Full-time Representative

Dec 2013 – Dec 2015

- Organized and led seminars focused on training 50+ representatives in effective volunteer practices
- Averaged 80+ hours a week teaching principles of hope, love, obedience, and self-reliance

# Youth Making a Difference

Salt Lake City, UT

Volunteer

Jan 2012 – Jan 2013

Raised \$2,000+ dollars throughout the course of a year to perform humanitarian work in rural India

#### **PERSONAL**

- Music songwriter and artist
- Alpine Skiing Coach, Sundance Resort
- Running, hiking, pickle ball, and ultimate disc enthusiast